<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/blog/tag/getting-started/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-01-15T18:05:38+00:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/tag/getting-started/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Desafinado | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>slightly out of tune</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The Sleeping Beauty Controversy</title>
      <link href="/blog/SB" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Sleeping Beauty Controversy" />
      <published>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/SB</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/SB">&lt;p&gt;Consider the following problem, stated here in the third person(Sleeping Beauty, or SB)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleeping Beauty agrees to the following experiment. On Sunday, she is put to sleep, and a fair coin si flipped.
If it comes up Heads, she is awakened on Monday morning; if Tails, she is awakened on Monday morning and again on Tuesday morning.
In all cases, she is not told the day of the week, is put back to sleep shortly after, and will have no memory of any Monday or Tuesday awakening.
When Sleeping Beauty is awakened on Monday or Tuesday, what–to her–is the probability that the coin came up Heads?&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Hahn</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Consider the following problem, stated here in the third person(Sleeping Beauty, or SB)</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">2018년 회고와 올해 계획</title>
      <link href="/blog/plan19" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018년 회고와 올해 계획" />
      <published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/plan19</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/plan19">&lt;p&gt;2018년 회고와 올해 계획&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2018년은 무척 즐거운 일들이 많았다. 회사에서는 새로운 부서에서 일하기 시작했고 다양한 사람들을 만날 수 있었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;회사일 외에도 몇몇 재미있는 프로젝트와 공부를 하였다. 정부지원사업의 성과평가에 대한 재밌는 공부를 했고, 계량경제학에서 발전하고 있는 정책효과 방법론에 대해 공부했다. 잔차를 통한 추론은 생각할수록 재미있는 주제다. 모르는 것들로부터 무엇을 알수 있을까?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;한양대에서 좋은 기회로 세미나를 진행하기도 했고, 경제학과에서 텍스트마이닝을 강의하였다. 물론 방송통신대학교에서의 졸업논문이 계기가 되었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;클라리넷은 찰리 파커의 곡을 연습해본 것이 재밌었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;올해에는 메커니즘 디자인에 대해 공부해보려 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;시간을 효율적으로 잘 써야겠다.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Hahn</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">2018년 회고와 올해 계획</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">2018년 새해 계획</title>
      <link href="/blog/plan" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018년 새해 계획" />
      <published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/plan</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/plan">&lt;p&gt;2018년 새해 계획&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;머릿속에 계획이 가장 많을 시간인 새해 첫날 즉흥적으로 올해 계획을 적는다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-theory-공부-및-실습&quot;&gt;Game theory 공부 및 실습&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;이론 공부하고 응용 econometirics로 확장하기.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;이론은 게임이론(왕규호,조인구), 게임이론과 진화 다이내믹스(최정규).  수학책이라 도움이 될지 모르겠지만 Mathematical Methods of Game and Economic Theory(Audin).  컴퓨터 사이언스 쪽의 책이라 도움이 될지 모르겠지만 Multiagent Systems-Algorithmic, Game-Theoretic, and Logical Foundations.  미시경제학, 네트워크 이론, 게임이론을 융합하려고 노력하는 Matthew O. Jackson의 Social and Economic Networks 이 정도로 공부해볼까 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘이론의 논리를 데이터에서 인식할 수 있는가’는 또 다른 광활한 영역이다. 미시경제학에서 계량경제학이 어떻게 쓰이는지 좀 알아봐야할 거 같다. Angrist의 Mostly Harmless Econometrics에서 출발해보려 한다.
게임이론과 계량경제학은 &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/~doubleh/papers/WC_editLydiaNov2010.pdf&quot;&gt;Game Theory and Econometrics: A Survey of Some Recent Research&lt;/a&gt;논문에서 출발점을 잡을 수 있지 않을까? 이렇게 블로그를 쓸 시간에 논문을 읽으면 어떻까?
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sigecom.org/exchanges/volume_14/1/SYRGKANIS.pdf&quot;&gt;Microsoft Research&lt;/a&gt;에서도 최근에 이런 주제를 다룬다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;데이터로부터 과점시장들을 식별하고 어떤 종류의 게임들이 가능하고 균형은 어떠한지. 이러한 작업이 가능하다면 어느 정도 깊이와 폭까지 나아갈 수 있을지 궁금하다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;통계학적-방법론-조금-더-나가기&quot;&gt;통계학적 방법론 조금 더 나가기&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;앤드류 겔만(Andrew Gelman)이 베이지안 통계학이 필요한 이유로 ‘데이터는 항상 부족하다.’라는 말을 했다고 한다. 하지만 prior 역시 항상 부족하다. 나의 성향이 데이터를 통한 일반화보다 로직을 데이터로 검증하는 것에 더 가까운 것 같다. 검증 문제가 아니라도 논리적 prior가 중요한 요소라고 생각한다. Game theory를 공부하려는 이유도 그렇다. 하지만 몇가지 통계학적 기법을 잘 익히는 것은 필요해 보인다. 그중에 눈에 들어오는 것이 Multi-level model에 대한 것이다. 이것은 하나 하나 보이는대로 해보기로 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;영어공부-하기&quot;&gt;영어공부 하기&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;이건 온라인 학원 구매해서 해보려 한다.^^* 토플 100점+alpha ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;지난-10여년간-직장생활-히스토리-정리하기&quot;&gt;지난 10여년간 직장생활 히스토리 정리하기&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;다사다난했던 2005년부터 현재까지 일인칭 작가 시점에서 써보고자 한다. 더 나아가면 학창 시절까지 써보고 싶다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;이것 밖에 없나?
나의 에고(ego) 작렬했던 시절 좋아했던 얀톤 체홉의 초상과 함께 올해 첫글을 쓴다.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Hahn</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">2018년 새해 계획</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">여름 가까운 어느날 꿈의 기록</title>
      <link href="/blog/memory" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="여름 가까운 어느날 꿈의 기록" />
      <published>2017-12-16T10:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-12-16T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/memory</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/memory">&lt;p&gt;숲속의 밤일까? 동굴 속의 밤일까?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;새까만 어둠 속 저 멀리서&lt;br /&gt;
예쁘게 빛나는 불빛들이 하울하울 춤추며 다가온다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;색들이 어둠 속에서 스스로 빛을 내는지&lt;br /&gt;
아니면 보이지 않는 곳에서 빛을 받는지 여러 색깔로 변해 가며 다가온다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;내가 누나에게 물었다 이게 무엇인지. 새벽이 올 땐 언제나 그랬단다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;새벽이 올 땐 언제나 아름다웠는데 모르고 살았구나.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;불빛들이 점점 다가오다가 드디어 내 앞을 지나간다.&lt;br /&gt;
점점이 빛나던 불빛들은 하얀 옷을 입은 어린아이들이 들고 있는 반짝이는 물건이었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;어린아이들이 나를 쳐다보며 지나가고 또 어디론가 나간다.&lt;br /&gt;
웃으며 나가기도 하고 나를 빤히 쳐다보며 나가기도 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;밖은 하얀 햇살이 쏟아지는 대낮이다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;첫째가 태어나기 몇 개월 전의 꿈이다.&lt;br /&gt;
언제부터인가 아름다우면서도 기억에 남는 꿈이 없다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;첫 글로 당시에 꿈을 글로 남겨놓았던 것을 가져왔다.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Hahn</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">숲속의 밤일까? 동굴 속의 밤일까?</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Welcome to Ghost</title>
      <link href="/blog/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ghost" />
      <published>2017-07-27T10:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-27T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/welcome</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt; posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-a-few-things-that-you-should-know-up-front&quot;&gt;There are a few things that you should know up-front:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so &lt;strong&gt;does&lt;/strong&gt; require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/pricing&quot;&gt;Ghost(Pro)&lt;/a&gt; service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: &lt;a href=&quot;https://demo.ghost.io/the-editor/&quot;&gt;the Ghost editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default &lt;strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/strong&gt; user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ghost</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Using the Ghost editor</title>
      <link href="/blog/the-editor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using the Ghost editor" />
      <published>2017-07-27T09:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-27T09:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/the-editor</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/the-editor">&lt;p&gt;Ghost uses a language called &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; to format text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a &lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;formattingtext&quot;&gt;Formatting text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common shortcuts are of course, &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; text, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com&quot;&gt;hyperlinks&lt;/a&gt;. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + B&lt;/code&gt; for Bold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + I&lt;/code&gt; for Italic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt; for a Link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + H&lt;/code&gt; for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;insertingimages&quot;&gt;Inserting images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Computer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; uploading them to Ghost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;makinglists&quot;&gt;Making lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. Like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crack the eggs over a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whisk them together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an omellete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to buy milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed the cat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with idea for next story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;addingquotes&quot;&gt;Adding quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividingthingsup&quot;&gt;Dividing things up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping &lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/advanced-markdown/&quot;&gt;Advanced Markdown Guide&lt;/a&gt; - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of &lt;a href=&quot;/using-tags/&quot;&gt;how to use Ghost tags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ghost</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Ghost uses a language called Markdown to format text. When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause. At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a ? icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts. For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used. Formatting text The most common shortcuts are of course, bold text, italic text, and hyperlinks. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts. CMD/Ctrl + B for Bold CMD/Ctrl + I for Italic CMD/Ctrl + K for a Link CMD/Ctrl + H for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc) With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story. Inserting images Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this: ![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg) Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown. Important Note: Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files before uploading them to Ghost. Making lists Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use * or - or +. Like this: Crack the eggs over a bowl Whisk them together Make an omellete or Remember to buy milk Feed the cat Come up with idea for next story Adding quotes When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &amp;gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients. A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly. Dividing things up If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping --- on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it. This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the Advanced Markdown Guide - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of how to use Ghost tags.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Organising your content with tags</title>
      <link href="/blog/using-tags" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organising your content with tags" />
      <published>2017-07-27T08:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-27T08:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/using-tags</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/using-tags">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ghost</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags. It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content. Basic tagging When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with News and other posts with Cycling, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on /tag/news/ and /tag/cycling/, respectively. If you tag a post with both News and Cycling - then it appears in both sections. Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data. The primary tag Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important. News, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports In this example, News is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives. Private tags Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling. For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do. News, Cycling, #video Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of News, and Cycling - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with #video. In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting: {{#post}} {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}} ...markup for a nice big video post layout... {{else}} ...regular markup for a post... {{/has}} {{/post}} You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive theme documentation.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Managing Ghost users</title>
      <link href="/blog/managing-users" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Managing Ghost users" />
      <published>2017-07-27T07:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-27T07:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/managing-users</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/managing-users">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are &lt;strong&gt;trusted&lt;/strong&gt; users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;editors&quot;&gt;Editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;administrators&quot;&gt;Administrators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;theowner&quot;&gt;The Owner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ghost</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team Authors The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are trusted users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin. Editors Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site. Administrators The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site. The Owner There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro). It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Making your site private</title>
      <link href="/blog/private-sites" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making your site private" />
      <published>2017-07-27T06:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-27T06:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/private-sites</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/private-sites">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's General Settings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/private.png&quot; alt=&quot;private&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do remember though, this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ghost</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase. You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's General Settings Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar. Do remember though, this is not secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Advanced Markdown tips</title>
      <link href="/blog/advanced-markdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advanced Markdown tips" />
      <published>2017-07-27T05:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-27T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/advanced-markdown</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/advanced-markdown">&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've gotten pretty comfortable with &lt;a href=&quot;/the-editor/&quot;&gt;all the basics&lt;/a&gt; of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you'll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we're using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;strike through&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;mark&gt;highlight&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writingcodeblocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using &lt;a href=&quot;http://prismjs.com/&quot;&gt;Prism.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullbleedimages&quot;&gt;Full bleed images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a &lt;code&gt;#hash&lt;/code&gt; value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/walking.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which is styled with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] {
    max-width: 100vw;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it's a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;referencelists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The quick brown &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fox&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Fox&quot;&gt;fox&lt;/a&gt;, jumped over the lazy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Dog&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;creatingfootnotes&quot;&gt;Creating footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quick brown fox&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; jumped over the lazy dog&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullhtml&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you're never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here's a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foxes are red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dogs are usually not red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Ghost</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Ghost editor If you've gotten pretty comfortable with all the basics of writing in Ghost, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown! As with the last post about the editor, you'll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we're using. Special formatting As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example: strike through highlight *escaped characters* Writing code blocks There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, like this. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks: .my-link { text-decoration: underline; } If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Prism.js. Full bleed images One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a #hash value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example: which is styled with... img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] { max-width: 100vw; } This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it's a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles. Reference lists The quick brown fox, jumped over the lazy dog. Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference. Creating footnotes The quick brown fox[1] jumped over the lazy dog[2]. Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post. Full HTML Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you're never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here's a standard YouTube embed code as an example: Foxes are red ↩︎ Dogs are usually not red ↩︎</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
